# João Tavares

Web Developer











A continuous learner, who looks forward to always exceed customers expectations.

Experienced developer, having already worked with a plethora of systems, languages and customers, is committed to find the best solutions in any kind of environment.

An excelent partner to work with, both for his good humour and optimism.

# **SKILLS**

### JAVASCRIPT/NODEJS

- \* MEAN Stack
- \* Mongoose
- \* Gulp/Grunt
- \* Ionic
- \* Cordova

### **LAMP STACK**

- \* Laravel
- \* HTML
- \* CSS
- \* Wordpress

#### AND...

- \* Delphi
- \* ASP
- \* Java
- \* C
- \* SQL Server
- \* PostgreSQL
- \* Bootstrap
- \* Git/Github
- \* GIMP
- \* UX/UI Design
- \* SCRUM
- \* Agile Development

# LANGUAGES

\* ENGLISH - IELTS General Level 7.0

\* FRENCH - Intermediate Advanced Level

\* SPANISH - Professional Level

\* PORTUGUESE - Native

# João **Tavares**

# EXPERIENCE

#### July 2016 to Present

### FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPMENT

Multiple Clients

After the conclusion of a specialization as Full Stack Developer, at the University of Hong Kong/Coursera, freelance works were done using mainly the MEAN Stack (MongoDB, Express, AngularJS, NodeJS), as well as the most recent technologies for both Front-end and Back-end. Besides, the best practices of programming were applied, like Mobile First design and Agile Development Techniques.

#### January 2009 to Present

### CHIÉF OF DATA CONSOLIDATION

MPDFT, Brasília, Brazil

In the Department of Alternative Ways of Emprisonment, strategic inside MPDFT and responsible for monitoring authors of minor crimes, was responsible for develop a system capable to register and control the compliance of tasks by convicted ones, like payments to NGOs or mandatory services done for those institutions. After implantation and continuous system evolution, the control done by the department was not only improved, but the values paid to the institutions has been increasing in an order of 12% yearly, helping those NGOs to better aid the society.

#### January 2003 to December 2008

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

MPDFT, Brasília, Brazil

Responsible for develop and maintain systems programmed in many different languages, like Java, ASP and mainly in Borland Delphi, all of them connected to a MS-SQL Server. At the peak, an average of 30 different systems were under responsability.

#### October 1999 to December 2002

### IT SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

MPDFT, Brasília, Brazil

Ranked 4th out 1200 candidates to the position of Informatics Technician at MPU, governmental institution, varied types of troubleshooting and device maintenance were done, like CPU formatting, HD images creation, antivirus installation, printers fixing, backups creation and restoring. The activities of Technical support were done both localy and remotely, via VNC.

## **EDUCATION**

\* Jan/18 to Present: UNYLEYA
Post-Graduate Certification in BigData (In progress)

\* Jul/16 to Jan/17: Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Full Stack Web Development Specialization

> \* Jan/98 to Dec/05: Universidade de Brasília Bachelor degree in Computer Science